purestorage.com 2019-08-15

# Pure Storage Privacy Policy | Pure Storage

Pure Storage, Inc. and its subsidiaries (collectively "Pure") are committed to protecting your personal information and providing you with a positive experience when visiting our websites and using our products and services ("Solution" or "Solutions"). By using Pure websites, Solutions, or otherwise providing personal information to us, you agree to the below terms, which may by updated from time to time. 

This Privacy Statement applies to Pure websites and Solutions that link to or reference this Statement and describes how we handle personal information and the choices available to you regarding collection, use, access, disclosure, and how to update and correct your personal information. Additional information on our personal information practices may be provided in offer descriptions, supplemental privacy statements, or notices provided prior to or at the time of data collection. Certain Pure websites may have their own privacy statement that describes how we handle personal information for those websites specifically. To the extent a notice provided at the time of collection or a website or Solution specific privacy statement conflict with this Privacy Statement, such specific notice or supplemental privacy statement will control.

**Compliance with Privacy Shield**

Pure complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention [privacy@purestorage.com](mailto:privacy@purestorage.com) of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States.  Pure has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

**Collecting Your Personal Information**

Pure may collect data, including personal information, about you as you use our websites and Solutions and interact with us.  For example, collection occurs when you complete a web form to request information about a Solution.

For purposes of this Privacy Statement, "personal information" is defined as any information that can be used to identify an individual, and may include; name, address, email address, phone number, login information (account number, password), marketing preferences, social media account information, or payment card number. If we link other data with your personal information, we will treat that linked data as personal information. We also collect personal information from trusted third-party sources and engage third parties to collect personal information to assist us.

Pure collects personal information for a variety of reasons, including, but not limited to:

  * Providing customer service and support for Solutions
  * Processing an order, including payment transactions
  * Sending marketing communications
  * Creating an account on a website or within a Solution
  * Enabling the use of certain features of our Solutions
  * Personalizing your view of Pure websites and/or Solution experience
  * Managing and processing a job application or job transfer
  * Providing you with a newsletter subscription
  * When a computer-based certification test is administered to you

Pure and the third parties with whom we engage may combine the information we collect from you over time and across our websites and Solutions with information obtained from other sources. This helps us improve its overall accuracy and completeness, and also helps us better tailor our interactions with you.

If you choose to provide Pure with a third party's personal information (such as name, email, and phone number), you represent that you have the third party's permission to do so and are responsible for such disclosure of that personal information.  Examples include forwarding reference or marketing material or sending job referrals. Third parties may unsubscribe at any time from any future communication by following the link provided to our [Data Subject Access Request](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/cffd69a9-f3ee-4bcf-8fc6-f61d1ddfe7f3) form the “DSAR Form”).   

In some instances, Pure and the third parties with whom we engage, may automatically collect data through cookies, web logs, web beacons, and other similar applications. This information is used to better understand and improve the usability, performance, and effectiveness of the website and to help tailor content or offers for you. Please read the "Cookies and Web Technologies" section below for more information.

**Uses of Your Personal Information**

Pure may use your personal information for a variety of reasons, including, but not limited to:

  * Providing customer service and support for Solutions
  * Processing an order, including payment transactions
  * Sending marketing communications
  * Creating an account on a website or within a Solution
  * Enabling the use of certain features of our Solutions
  * Personalizing your view of Pure websites and/or Solution experience
  * Managing and processing a job application or job transfer
  * Providing you with a newsletter subscription
  * When a computer-based certification test is administered to you
  * For other legitimate purposes permitted by applicable law or to comply with a legal or mandatory obligation.

**Rights of Individuals to Access Personal Information**

You can exercise your rights of access and request corrections, suppression, or deactivations with applicable data protection laws.  If you need additional assistance, or help accessing, correcting, suppressing, or deleting your personal information, please submit a request via the DSAR Form or email us at [privacy@purestorage.com](mailto:privacy@purestorage.com).

We make good faith efforts to honor reasonable requests to access, correct, suppress, or delete your data. We will respond to your request within 30 days or as otherwise mandated by applicable data protection laws. If we are unable to honor your good faith request, we will provide you with an explanation. Under certain circumstances, you have rights under applicable data protection laws in relation to the access, correction, suppression, or deletion of your personal information. Should you wish to exercise those rights, please submit a request via the DSAR Form or email us at [privacy@purestorage.com](mailto:privacy@purestorage.com).

Please note that we may need to request specific information from you to confirm your identity and right to access your personal information. This is a security measure to ensure personal information is not disclosed to any person or third party who does not have a right to receive it. To efficiently process your request, we may contact you for further information.  With your permission, we may also share your personal information with Pure business partners or vendors and, they may send you information about products or services that may be of interest to you. To opt-out of receiving information from third parties for their marketing purposes, please submit a request via the DSAR Form or email us at [privacy@purestorage.com](mailto:privacy@purestorage.com).

**The choices Pure offers individuals to limit the use and disclosure of personal information**

Pure offers individuals two methods to limit the use of and disclosure of personal information:

  * Submit a request by using the DSAR Form; or
  * Email [privacy@purestorage.com](mailto:privacy@purestorage.com) **.**

**The types of Third Parties to which Pure discloses personal information and the purposes for doing so.**

Pure may share your personal information with third parties for the purposes of operating our business, delivering, improving, and customizing our Solutions, sending marketing and other communications related to our business, and for other legitimate purposes permitted by applicable law or otherwise with your consent.

Pure may disclose personal information to third parties for a variety of reasons, including but not limited to:

  * Within Pure and any of our global subsidiaries for purposes of data processing or storage.
  * With Pure business partners or vendors, so that they may share information with you about their products or services.
  * With business partners, service vendors, authorized third-party agents, or contractors to provide a requested Solution, service or transaction.
  * In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, consolidation or restructuring, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by or to another company.
  * In response to a request for information by a competent authority if we believe disclosure is in accordance with, or is otherwise required by, any applicable law, regulation or legal process.
  * In aggregated and/or anonymized form which cannot reasonably be used to identify you.
  * If we otherwise notify you and you consent to the disclosure.

**Disclosure of Personal Information In Response To Lawful Requests By Public Authorities**

Pure will disclose personal information with law enforcement officials, government authorities, or other third parties as necessary to comply with legal process or meet national security requirements; protect the rights, property, or safety of Pure, its business partners, you, or others; or as otherwise required by applicable law.

**What is the possibility of an individual invoking binding arbitration?**

Pure’s employment offer letters contain binding arbitration provisions for U.S. employees only (for any disputes, claims, or causes of action, in law or equity, arising from or relating to the enforcement, breach, performance, or interpretation of the offer, their employment with the Company, or the termination of their employment).  Employees outside the U.S. may be subject to other binding resolution processes.

**Pure’s Liability in Onward Transfers to Third Parties**

Pure uses standard contract clauses to fulfill contractual requirements for onward transfers to third parties.

**Selecting Your Communication Preferences**

Pure gives you the choice of receiving a variety of information related to our Solutions. You can manage your communication preferences through the following methods:

  * By submitting a request via the DSAR Form.
  * By following the instructions included in each promotional email from Pure to unsubscribe from that particular mailing.
  * By sending us a message through email to: [privacy@purestorage.com](mailto:privacy@purestorage.com) or by regular mail to: Pure Storage, Inc., Attn: Chief Compliance Officer, 650 Castro Street #200, Mountain View, CA 94041.

Regardless of which method you choose to select your communication preferences, please be sure to include your name, email address, and specific, relevant information about the material you no longer wish to receive. These choices do not apply to service notifications or other required communications that are considered part of certain Solutions, which you may receive periodically unless you stop using or cancel the Solution in accordance with its terms and conditions.

We may also share your personal information with Pure business partners or vendors, so they may send you information about products or services that may be of interest to you. To opt-out of receiving information from third parties for their marketing purposes, please submit a request via the DSAR Form or email [privacy@purestorage.com](mailto:privacy@purestorage.com).

By using our websites, Solutions, or otherwise providing personal information to us, you agree that we may communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use.

**Sharing Your Personal Information**

Pure may share personal information for a variety of reasons, including but not limited to:

  * Within Pure and any of our global subsidiaries for purposes of data processing or storage.
  * With Pure business partners or vendors, so that they may share information with you about their products or services.
  * With business partners, service vendors, authorized third-party agents, or contractors to provide a requested Solution, service or transaction. Examples include, but are not limited to: processing of orders and credit card transactions, hosting websites, hosting seminar registration, assisting with sales-related efforts or post-sales support, and providing customer support.
  * In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, consolidation or restructuring, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by or to another company.
  * In response to a request for information by a competent authority if we believe disclosure is in accordance with, or is otherwise required by, any applicable law, regulation or legal process.
  * With law enforcement officials, government authorities, or other third parties as necessary to comply with legal process or meet national security requirements; protect the rights, property, or safety of Pure, its business partners, you, or others; or as otherwise required by applicable law.
  * In aggregated and/or anonymized form which cannot reasonably be used to identify you.
  * If we otherwise notify you and you consent to the sharing.

To opt-out of Pure sharing with third parties for their marketing purposes, please submit a request via the DSAR Form or email us at [privacy@purestorage.com](mailto:privacy@purestorage.com).

**Security of Your Personal Information**

We intend to protect the personal information entrusted to us and treat it securely in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Pure implements physical, administrative, and technical safeguards designed to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. We contractually require that our suppliers protect such information from unauthorized access, use, and disclosure. Notwithstanding the measures Pure takes to protect your personal information, it does not guarantee the security of any personal information you provide to us or third parties.

**Retention of Personal Information**

We will only retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected, or as necessary to comply with our business requirements and necessary laws; to comply with any legal, accounting or reporting obligations; to resolve disputes; to protect our assets; to efficiently run our business; and to enforce our agreements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes for which we collect or process your personal information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

**Use of Cookies and Web Technologies**

Like many websites, Pure uses automatic data collection tools, such as cookies, embedded web links, and web beacons. These tools collect certain standard information that your browser sends to our website such as your browser type and the address of the website from which you arrived at our website. They may also collect information about:

  * Your Internet Protocol (IP) address. This is a number automatically assigned to your computer or device whenever you are connecting to the Internet. It allows web servers to locate and identify your device, this is a unique address assigned to your device by your Internet service provider or information systems department on a TCP/IP network.
  * Clickstream behavior, which helps us better understand your visit to our website and may, in turn, provide you with a more customized experience when you return.

The Pure website includes widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our site to provide specific services from another company (such as displaying the news, opinions, music, and more). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through such widgets. Cookies may also be set by widgets to enable it to function properly. Information collected by widgets is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created the widget.

Some web browsers may give you the ability to enable a "do not track" feature that sends signals to the websites you visit, indicating that you do not want your online activities tracked. This is different than blocking or deleting cookies, as browsers with a "do not track" feature enabled may still accept cookies. There is currently no industry standard for how companies should respond to "do not track" signals, although one may develop in the future. Our websites do not recognize and respond to "do not track" signals at this time. If that changes in the future, it will be reflected in our most updated Privacy Statement.

**Linked Websites**

We may provide links to other third-party websites and services that are outside our control and not covered by this Privacy Statement. We encourage you to review the privacy statements posted on those websites (and all websites) you visit.

**Forums and Chat Rooms**

If you participate in a discussion forum, local communities, or chat room on a Pure website, you should be aware that the information you provide there (i.e. your public profile) may be made broadly available to others, and could be used to contact you, send you unsolicited messages, or for purposes neither Pure, nor you, have control over. Also, please recognize that individual forums and chat rooms may have additional rules and conditions. Pure is not responsible for the personal information or any other information you choose to submit in these forums. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, please submit a request via the DSAR Form or email us at [privacy@purestorage.com](mailto:privacy@purestorage.com). In certain circumstances, we may not be able to remove your personal information.

**Consent to Transfer, Processing and Storage of Personal Information**

As Pure is a global organization, we may transfer your personal information to Pure in the United States of America, to any Pure subsidiary worldwide, or to third parties and business partners as described above that are located in various countries around the world. By using our websites and Solutions or providing any personal information to us, where applicable law permits, you consent to the collection, use, disclosure, sharing, retention, transfer, and processing of such information outside of your country of residence where data protection laws and regulations may be different.

Whenever we transfer your personal information out of the European Economic Area (“EEA”), we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by the use of specific contracts approved by the European Commission which provides the same protection to  personal information as it has in Europe.

**Independent Recourse Mechanism for Privacy Shield Complaints**

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Pure commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information.  EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Pure at: [privacy@purestorage.com](mailto:privacy@purestorage.com)

Pure has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning human resources data transferred from the EU in the context of the employment relationship.

**Subject to Investigatory and Regulatory Powers of the FTC**

Pure is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

**Liability for onward transfers to third parties**

Pure has liability for onward transfers to third parties unless we can prove we were not a party to the events giving rise to the damages.

**How to Contact Us**

We value your opinions. Should you have questions or comments related to this Privacy Statement, please email [privacy@purestorage.com](mailto:privacy@purestorage.com).

**Updates to this Pure Privacy Statement**

We may update this Privacy Statement from time to time. If we modify our Privacy Statement, we will post the revised version at www.purestorage.com.

**This Privacy Statement was last updated on August 5, 2019.**
